This means, "I'm smiling."
هذه تعني اني ابتسم.
So does that.
وكذلك تلك.
This means "mouse."
هذه تعني فأر.
"Cat."
قطة.
Here we have a story.
هنا لدينا قصة.
The start of the story, where this means guy,
بداية القصة، حيث يعني هذا شخص،
and that is a ponytail on a passer-by.
وهذا ذيل الحصان علي راسه.
Here's where it happens.
هنا حيث حدث.
These are when.
وهنا متي تم.
This is a cassette tape the girl puts into her cassette-tape player.
هذا شريط تسجيل والفتاة تضعه علي مشغل التسجيل.
She wears it every day.
هي تحمله كل يوم.
It's not considered vintage --
تلك لا تُعتبر
she just likes certain music to sound a certain way.
إنها تحب فقط أن تصدر موسيقى محددة صوتاً بطريقة محددة.
Look at her posture; it's remarkable.
أنظر إلى موقفها، إنه مميز.
That's because she dances.
ذلك لأنها ترقص.
Now he, the guy, takes all of this in, figuring,
الآن، هو الرجل، يأخذ كل هذا، يتعرف عليه،
"Honestly, geez, what are my chances?"
"بصراحة، يا إلهي، يا للفرصة؟"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And he could say, "Oh my God!"
وكان بوسعه القول، "اوه يا إلهي!"
or "I heart you!"
او "لقد اذيتك!"
"I'm laughing out loud."
انا اضحك بصوت عالي.
"I want to give you a hug."
اريد ان احضنك.
But he comes up with that, you know.
لكنه توصل لذلك، كما تعلمون.
He tells her, "I'd like to hand-paint your portrait on a coffee mug."
هو يخبرها، "أرغب في رسم صورتك على كوب قهوتك."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Put a crab inside it.
ضع سرطان البحر بداخلها.
Add some water.
و قليل من المياه.
Seven different salts.
سبعة اشكال من الملح.
He means he's got this sudden notion to stand on dry land,
إنه يعني أنه حصل على فكرته الفجائية ليقف على أرض جافة،
but just panhandle at the ocean.
لكنه أنتهى عند المحيط.
He says, "You look like a mermaid, but you walk like a waltz."
هو يقول، " أنت تبدين كحورية البحر، لكنك تمشين مثل راقص الفالس."
And the girl goes, "Wha'?"
وتقول الفتاة، " ماذا؟"
So, the guy replies, "Yeah, I know, I know.
لذا، يرد عليها الرجل، " نعم، أعرف، أعرف.
I think my heartbeat might be the Morse code for inappropriate.
أعتقد أن نبضات قلبي ربما تكون غير مناسبة لشفرة مورس.
At least, that's how it seems.
على الأقل، هكذا تبدو.
I'm like a junior varsity cheerleader sometimes --
أنا أحب صغار مشجعي الاسكواتش بعض الأحيان--
for swearing, awkward silences, and very simple rhyme schemes.
لأداء اليمين ، إحراج الصمت ، والقوافي المنظمة البسيطة جدا.
Right now, talking to you, I'm not even really a guy.
حالياً، أتحدث معك، أنا لست رجلاً حقيقي حتى.
I'm a monkey --
أنا قرد،
(Laughter) --
(ضحك)
blowing kisses
تهب القبلات
at a butterfly.
في فراشة
But I'm still suggesting you and I should meet.
لكن مازلت أقترح لك أننا يجب أن نلتقي.
First, soon, and then a lot.
أولاً، قريباً، ثم كثيراً.
I'm thinking the southwest corner of 5th and 42nd at noon tomorrow,
أنا أفكر بناصية جنوب قرب يوم الخامس والثاني والأربعين ظهر يوم غد،
but I'll stay until you show up, ponytail or not.
لكني سأنتظر حتى تأتين، ذيل الحصان أو لا.
Hell, ponytail alone.
الجحيم، ذيل الحصان وحده.
I don't know what else to tell you.
لا أعرف ماذا أيضاً لأخبرك به.
I got a pencil you can borrow.
لدي قلم رصاص يمكنك إستعارته.
You can put it in your phone."
يمكنك وضعه على هاتفك."
But the girl does not budge, does not smile, does not frown.
لكن الفتاة لا تتزحزح، لا تبتسم، لا تعبس.
She just says, "No thank you."
تقول فقط، " لا شكراً لك."
You know?
تعلمون؟
[ "i don't need 2 write it down." ]
["لا أحتاج لكتابة ذلك."]
(Applause)
(تصفيق)